Animesh Sharma

Software Engineer

Professional Summary _

Software engineer with 2 years of experience in full-stack web development specializing in ReactJS, NodeJS, HTML, CSS, and PostgreSQL. Experienced in Agile methodologies and SDLC. Collaborated with cross-functional teams of up to 15 members including collaborations with teams outside of the company

Contact Information

Email: <u>animesh.sharmag96@gmail.com</u>

Location: Bangalore, India Phone: +91-9066480828

Github: https://github.com/animax-it

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/animesh-sharma-0b5a04151/

Portfolio: https://animeshfolio.netlify.app/

Skills

Programming HTML/CSS, JavaScript, SQL

Frameworks & Libraries ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, NextJS, 3JS

Databases MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Work Experience _____

PinkBlue Supply Solutions

Software Engineer Feb 2023 – Present

- Optimized user onboarding by implementing single-click WhatsApp login, reducing the process time from 1 minute to 10 seconds
- Streamlined delivery information entry by integrating Google Maps API, reducing the time from 2 minutes to 5 seconds and improving address accuracy
- Designed a custom coupon page, resulting in a 10% increase in coupon utilization
- Designed and engineered product review feature with image upload and rating, increased order conversion rate by 20%
- Addressed and resolved a significant number of bugs and implemented UI improvements throughout the website, resulting in a 30% decrease in customer-reported issues
- Added a robust product search functionality reducing average search time by 25%
- Optimized banner image loading on the landing page resulting in a 50% faster loading time
- Increased app usage by 20% by converting the progressive web app into a desktop adaptive site.

Eagleview

Software Engineer Nov 2020 - Dec 2022

- Developed tools to automate the manual process of capturing screenshots, saving the IG team 70 hours per week.
- Built and maintained UI for different microservices utilized by the operations team (Twister, Image Grabber, FTM).
- Utilized HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and ReactJS for responsive web development, implementing CI/CD pipelines for streamlined and efficient deployment processes
- Worked on UI development for tools that format aerial images of properties from all directions, resulting in a 90% reduction in manual errors during property measurements

Education
Bangalore Institute of Technology
Bangalore B.E in Civil Engineering 2015 – 2019
Projects
Marvel Shop
An e-commerce website with modern design and animations with products, advanced cart, checkout, and payment integration (NextJS and Sanity)
Face Mesh
Real-time AI face landmark detection which recognizes and points out the different facial features (TensorFlow and React)
Memories
Social Media App with posts, likes and comments (React-Redux and MERN)
Sentiment Analyzer
An app which displays the nature of the sentence input by the user (NLTK and React)
Portfolio Website
Static website with About, Contact and Projects (3JS, Vite and HTML)
Awarda
Awards
2021 Elite, Python for Data Science NPTEL Exam India
Certifications
Online Courses

- Introduction to Cloud Computing IBM
- Introduction to Web Development with HTML, CSS, JavaScript IBM
- Getting Started with Git and GitHub IBM